<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tip on A byte of learning</title>
    <link>/tags/tip/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tip on A byte of learning</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tip/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The humble ellipsis or three dots in R functions</title>
      <link>/post/the-humble-ellipsis-or-three-dots-in-r-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-humble-ellipsis-or-three-dots-in-r-functions/</guid>
      <description>So, I was writing a function and within that function, I needed to call the mean function.
Of course, mean can take many arguments (see ?mean) and one of them is na.rm. I didn’t want to have na.rm as a required input in my function. I found that the way to have additional variable number of inputs in an r function is the ellipsis or three-dots operator.
A very trivial implementation is as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cut a vector into n-tiles</title>
      <link>/post/cut-a-vector-into-n-tiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cut-a-vector-into-n-tiles/</guid>
      <description>Useful code to cut vector into ntiles in R To break a numeric vector X into n-tiles (e.g, here into quartiles), use
y &amp;lt;- cut(X, breaks=c(quantile(X, probs = seq(0, 1, by = 0.25))), labels=c(&amp;quot;L1&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;L2&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;L3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;L4&amp;quot;)) Somehow, the syntax highligting is not upto mark … :( This code fragment looks much better on rouge even though, jekyll 3 is supposed to be using rouge for syntax highlighting, don’t know why this is happening or how to resolve this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facetime Camera Fix</title>
      <link>/post/facetime-camera-fix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/facetime-camera-fix/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes when I want to use facetime, the camera does not start automatically. Usually happens, when I have used Skype just before using facetime. Here is the fix for it, paste the following commands in the console
sudo killall AppleCameraAssistant;sudo killall VDCAssistant which I found here. Then, restart facetime. Hopefully, it will work after executing the commands above.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>